<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Critical Thinking on Agones</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/critical-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Critical Thinking on Agones</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:25:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/critical-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Types of Questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/types-of-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/types-of-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6083-Types-of-Questions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Types of Questions&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;types-of-questions&#34;&gt;Types of Questions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Question-Answering task is one of the tasks in NLP-Task. To create a high-performing AI system that can understand the question correctly and answer appropriately, we need to train a model. And to train a model, we need to have a good-quality dataset in place. Without understanding what are the different formats of questions and answers, we cannot create a dataset. In our day-to-day life we never pay attention to this minute detail but to create an AI system that can perform QA tasks, we need to understand the different formats of questions. In this article, I am creating a list of these different types of questions. To create an AI system that can perform all these kinds of QA tasks, we need to craft the dataset very carefully. Although, we see lots of data around, but to create an NLP-Task specific dataset is tedious task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Biases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/cognitive-biases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/cognitive-biases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6051-Cognitive-Biases.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cognitive Bias&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;cognitive-biases&#34;&gt;Cognitive Biases&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cognitive biases are the systematic errors that occur when individuals deviate from rational decision-making. These biases are a result of our brain&amp;rsquo;s ability to process information, which can sometimes lead to irrational thinking and decision-making. As data science continues to advance, it is critical to understand how cognitive biases can impact AI, ML, NLP, deep learning, and robotics. Cognitive biases can lead to biased data collection, modeling, and decision-making processes, which can ultimately impact the accuracy and effectiveness of these technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Reasoning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/The-Science-of-Reasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 15:50:00 +0530</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/The-Science-of-Reasoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-science-of-reasoning&#34;&gt;The Science of Reasoning&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6017-The-Science-of-Reasoning.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Science of Reasoning&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-reasoning&#34;&gt;About Reasoning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reasoning is a unique ability in humans. Whatever civilizational advancement we see, it is because of our ability to think, imagine and reason. We all give reasons and ask for reasons but most humans don&amp;rsquo;t understand the fallacies of reasoning. Due to this sometimes we are putting forward a correct point but we are using the wrong reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Sanskrit, we have a subject called Tarka Shastra, which deals with reasoning. My purpose of writing this article is neither to guide you for some career exam nor to make you a TV debater, but to summarize the importance of correct reasoning. If you know what is the correct way of reasoning then nobody can confuse you and the most important thing, you will not confuse yourself and feel a victim of society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
