<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence on Agones</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence on Agones</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:25:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Physics with Deeper Questions with ChatGPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/quantum-physics-with-deeper-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/quantum-physics-with-deeper-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6253-quantum-physics-with-deeper-questions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Quantum Physics with Deeper Questions&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;quantum-physics-with-deeper-questions-with-chatgpt&#34;&gt;Quantum Physics with Deeper Questions with ChatGPT&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was a physics student during my college years, and I’ve always loved the subject—even today. However, Quantum Physics, despite all my reading and learning, remains a mystery to me. At this stage, who can teach me Quantum Physics effectively? Finding an able professor, aligning my availability with theirs, and hoping they’d be willing to teach me for free seems impossible. So, I turned to a Large Language Model (LLM) for help. I could have explored other LLMs like Grok, Claude, DeepSeek, and many more. I’m not saying the others are bad, nor am I claiming that ChatGPT is the best at providing plausible answers. Whether an answer is correct or plausible also depends on the learner’s ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Predictions for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/ai-predictions-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/ai-predictions-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6197-Major-AI-Predictions-for-2025.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Predictions for 2025&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-ai-predictions-for-2025&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major AI Predictions for 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;listen-summary-of-this-in-podcast-format&#34;&gt;Listen Summary of this in Podcast Format&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;audio controls&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;source src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dasarpai/DAI-mp3/main/Transcripts-2-Audio/AI-Predictions-2025.wav&#34; type=&#34;audio/wav&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Your browser does not support the audio element.&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/audio&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-predictions-for-2025&#34;&gt;AI Predictions for 2025&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-ai-agents-and-autonomous-tools&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. AI Agents and Autonomous Tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI agents will become ubiquitous, capable of autonomously performing tasks like booking flights, scheduling meetings, or managing workflows. The term &amp;ldquo;agentic&amp;rdquo; will become commonplace.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-ai-integration-in-everyday-life&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. AI Integration in Everyday Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI technology will be embedded into household appliances (e.g., refrigerators, ovens, and laundry machines) and wearables (e.g., sunglasses, earbuds) for enhanced functionality. Human and appliances will be able to talk with each other.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generative AI characters will be introduced on social media platforms for engagement and interaction. These characters will adopt different styles and personalities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-growth-in-ai-wearables&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Growth in AI Wearables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smart wearables like heads-up display glasses and earbuds offering real-time translation will gain popularity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You will be able to learn language easily while talking with your wearables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-video-models-and-content-creation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Video Models and Content Creation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI video generation models will advance to the point where AI-generated videos become indistinguishable from real ones, potentially passing the &amp;ldquo;Visual Turing Test.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI tools for converting long-form videos into short clips will make content creation easier for creators.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI will also play a covert or overt role in movie production, possibly resulting in AI-created movies becoming a trend.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-ai-in-entertainment-and-gaming&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. AI in Entertainment and Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI-driven entertainment robots and video content will grow, enabling creators to produce work faster.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gaming technology advancements will include dynamic resolution upscaling through deep learning super sampling (DLSS). It uses deep learning algorithms to upscale lower-resolution images to higher resolutions, enhancing the visual quality of games without significantly impacting performance. This allows for higher graphical settings and smoother frame rates, making games look better and run more efficiently&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-self-driving-and-autonomous-vehicles&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Self-Driving and Autonomous Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Significant developments in self-driving technology, with advancements from companies like Tesla, Waymo (google), and Lyft (Amazon). Tesla might achieve unsupervised full self-driving capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-quantum-computing-progress&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Quantum Computing Progress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Breakthroughs in quantum computing with new chips from Google and IBM.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-ai-in-workspaces-and-business&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. AI in Workspaces and Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI integration into workspaces for streamlined operations and minimal supervision.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Businesses will increasingly rely on AI for operational efficiency and innovation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-challenges-of-ai-generated-content&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Challenges of AI-Generated Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Proliferation of low-quality, AI-generated content flooding platforms (termed &amp;ldquo;AI slop&amp;rdquo;), leading to potential SEO penalties and a need for better content regulation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SEO business will be completely revamped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ethical challenges in discerning AI-generated content from real content will drive the need for verification systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People will become less reactive to even real videos/audio/content, because of the flood of AI-generated content.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-ai-ethics-regulation-and-identity-verification&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. AI Ethics, Regulation, and Identity Verification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Growing discussions on ethics and regulations around AI, particularly with the emergence of personal AI assistants and concerns over privacy and bias.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blockchain-based &amp;ldquo;proof of personhood&amp;rdquo; solutions to verify identities in the face of AI advancements. This year Blockchain will enter into the mainstream along with AI app development.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-hybrid-creativity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Hybrid Creativity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI will evolve as a creative partner in art, music, and content creation, enabling &amp;ldquo;hybrid creativity&amp;rdquo; between humans and machines.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To create content whatever technology and tools you need, you can use those easily with AI copilots and AI assistants.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-extended-reality-xr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Extended Reality (XR)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XR technologies will become mainstream, particularly through compact, user-friendly devices like AI-powered glasses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI will enter into the realm of virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR) to provide immersive experiences.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;13-regenerative-medicine&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Regenerative Medicine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI-driven advancements in regenerative medicine, although progress might be slowed by legal and ethical challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;14-customizable-social-media-algorithms&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Customizable Social Media Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Social media platforms may offer users the ability to fine-tune their algorithms for a personalized experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;15-ai-compute-and-applications&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15. AI Compute and Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GPU power will increase more and they will become cheaper and widely available for local AI workloads.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;16-ai-in-programming&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16. AI in Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI will be commonly used for product development, architecture, UML, code completion, code refactoring, debugging, and testing. So, the cost and time of development will reduce and quality will improve.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI written code will selfheal if it is failing, improve for performance and security.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-readings&#34;&gt;Related Readings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My 2020, article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dsblog/100&amp;#43;High-Level-AI-Usecases&#34;&gt;100+ AI Usecase - Future Predictions for AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Types of Large Language Models (LLM)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Types-of-LLM/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Types-of-LLM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6171-Types-of-LLM.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world of Generative AI (GenAI) is expanding at an astonishing rate, with new models emerging almost daily, each sporting unique names, capabilities, versions, and sizes. For AI professionals, keeping track of these models can feel like a full-time job. But for business users, IT professionals, and software developers trying to make the right choice, understanding the model’s name and what it represents can seem overwhelming. Wouldn’t it be helpful if we could decode the meaning behind these names to know if a model fits our needs and is worth the investment? In this article, we’ll break down how the names of GenAI models can reveal clues about their functionality and suitability for specific tasks, helping you make informed decisions with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI/ML with Oracle Cloud</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/AI-ML-With-Oracle-Cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/AI-ML-With-Oracle-Cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6166-AI-ML-With-Oracle-Cloud.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI/ML with Oracle Cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;aiml-with-oracle-cloud&#34;&gt;AI/ML with Oracle Cloud&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;oracle-infrastructure-services&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/Content/services.htm&#34;&gt;Oracle Infrastructure Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Register for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/cloud/free/?source=:ow:o:h:po:OHPPanel1nav0625&amp;amp;intcmp=:ow:o:h:po:OHPPanel1nav0625&#34;&gt;Oracle Cloud Free Tier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;oracle-ai-main-services&#34;&gt;Oracle AI Main services&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.oracle.com/digital-assistant/oda-instances?region=ap-mumbai-1&#34;&gt;Digital Assistant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/Content/document-understanding/using/home.htm&#34;&gt;Document Understanding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/language/using/pretrain-models.htm#lang-detect&#34;&gt;Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/Content/vision/using/pretrained-model-using-image.htm&#34;&gt;Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/Content/speech/home.htm&#34;&gt;Speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/Content/Streaming/home.htm&#34;&gt;Stream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/process-automation/oci-process-automation/overview-oci-process-automation.html&#34;&gt;Cloud Infra Automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;generative-ai&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/en-us/iaas/Content/generative-ai/home.htm&#34;&gt;Generative AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is a fully managed Oracle Cloud Infrastructure service that provides a set of state-of-the-art, customizable large language models (LLMs) that cover a wide range of use cases, including chat, text generation, summarization, and creating text embeddings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Skills and Human Skills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/LLM-Skills-and-Human-Skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/LLM-Skills-and-Human-Skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6130-LLM-Skills-and-Human-Skills.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LLM-Skills-and-Human-Skills&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;llm-skills-and-human-skills&#34;&gt;LLM Skills and Human Skills&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-skill&#34;&gt;What is skill?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A skill is the ability to perform a task or activity effectively and efficiently. It involves applying knowledge, experience, and techniques to achieve specific outcomes. Skills can be categorized into various types, including:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hard Skills: Technical abilities that are often measurable and specific to a job or field, such as programming, writing, or playing an instrument.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soft Skills: Interpersonal and personal attributes that enable someone to interact effectively with others, such as communication, teamwork, and problem-solving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>God Fathers of AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/God-Fathers-of-AI/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/God-Fathers-of-AI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6058-God-Fathers-of-AI.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;God Fathers of AI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;god-fathers-of-ai&#34;&gt;God Fathers of AI&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In other fields of studies or in religion, there is only one god or only one godfather. But in the field of AI, that is not the case. There are many pioneers or Godfathers who have done significant work in this field. Recently, the resignation of Dr. Geoffrey Hinton from Google raised eyebrows in the business world and in Governments the world over. Technology is good or bad, it depends upon whose hand it is. Geoffrey raised that concern and for that, he wants better controls in place. What will happen, we need to follow the progress and raise our voices around. In this article, I am mentioning some godfathers of AI, their workplaces, and their contributions. I am sure this will inspire many young minds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Types of Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Types-of-Machine-Learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Types-of-Machine-Learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6056-Types-of-Machine-Learning.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Types of Machine Learning&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;types-of-machine-learning&#34;&gt;Types of Machine Learning&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is a field of artificial intelligence that focuses on developing algorithms that can learn from data and make predictions or decisions. There are several types of machine learning techniques, each with its strengths and weaknesses. In this post, we will explore some of the most commonly used machine learning techniques, including supervised learning, unsupervised learning, reinforcement learning, and more. This post is not about deep diving into these topics but to give you a oneliner understanding and the difference between these different techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Replace Human?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Will-AI-Replace-Human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 08:33:00 +0530</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Will-AI-Replace-Human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6038-Will-AI-Replace-Human.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Will AI Replace Human&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;artificial-intelligence-can-replace-human&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence can Replace Human?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Success of ChatGPT has taken the world by storm. Unless you are not living in some cave you already know what is happening. People are asking questions like will AI replace humans? What will happen to our jobs? What are the challenges? I thought let me write my thought on this. There was significant overlap between these phases, so don&amp;rsquo;t assume that when one phase was over then only the second started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Neural Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Introduction-to-Neural-Network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/Introduction-to-Neural-Network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6034-Introduction-to-Neural-Network.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Introduction to Neural Network&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-neural-network&#34;&gt;Introduction to Neural Network&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-a-perceptron&#34;&gt;Introduction to a Perceptron&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A perceptron is a type of artificial neural network that can be used for binary classification. It is a simple model that consists of a single layer of artificial neurons and is used to classify input data into one of two categories. The perceptron algorithm learns the weights of the artificial neurons by adjusting them based on the input data and the desired output. The perceptron is considered a basic building block for more complex neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in Energy Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/AI-in-Energy-Management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/AI-in-Energy-Management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6046-AI-Usecases-in-Energy-Management.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI in Energy Management&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ai-in-energy-management&#34;&gt;AI in Energy Management&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The application of AI in energy management is aimed at optimizing energy consumption and reducing waste in the energy sector. AI can help in Energy Demand management, Energy Optimization, Energy Equipment Maintenance and Repair, Renewable energy integration and smart grid management. Some of the specific usecases in Energy sector can be as following.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;important-specific-usecases-of-ai-in-energy-management&#34;&gt;Important specific usecases of AI in Energy Management&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Real-time monitoring: AI can be used to monitor energy consumption in real-time, providing real-time feedback on energy usage patterns and allowing for immediate adjustments to improve energy efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Predictive maintenance: AI algorithms can be used to predict when equipment is likely to fail, reducing downtime and improving the reliability of energy systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy trading: AI algorithms can be used to optimize energy trading by predicting energy prices and enabling the buying and selling of energy at optimal times.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grid balancing: AI can be used to balance energy supply and demand in real-time, reducing energy waste and improving the reliability of energy grids.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Carbon emissions reduction: AI algorithms can be used to analyze energy consumption patterns and identify ways to reduce carbon emissions, helping to mitigate the impact of energy consumption on the environment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy storage optimization: AI algorithms can be used to optimize the use of energy storage systems, reducing energy waste and improving energy efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy efficiency assessment: AI can be used to assess the energy efficiency of buildings, factories, and other energy-intensive environments, providing recommendations for improvement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Renewable energy forecasting: AI can be used to forecast renewable energy generation, helping energy providers to better match supply and demand and reduce energy waste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smart meter data analysis: AI algorithms can be used to analyze data from smart meters, providing insights into energy consumption patterns and enabling better energy management.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy-saving behavior analysis: AI algorithms can be used to analyze energy-saving behaviors of consumers, providing insights into ways to reduce energy waste and improve efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy market analysis: AI algorithms can be used to analyze energy markets, providing insights into energy prices and enabling better energy trading.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy fraud detection: AI algorithms can be used to detect energy fraud, reducing energy waste and improving the reliability of energy systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy efficiency incentives: AI algorithms can be used to analyze energy consumption patterns and determine appropriate incentives for consumers to reduce energy waste and improve efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the application of AI in energy management is a promising solution for improving energy efficiency and reducing energy waste. By using AI algorithms to analyze data and predict energy consumption patterns, energy providers can better match supply and demand, reduce energy waste, and lower costs. Furthermore, the use of AI in energy management has the potential to mitigate the impact of energy consumption on the environment, improve reliability, and provide insights into ways to reduce energy waste and increase efficiency. The future of AI in energy management is bright, and as AI technologies continue to advance, it is likely that new and innovative applications will emerge that will further transform the energy sector and benefit consumers and the environment alike&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100&#43; High Level AI Usecases and Future Prediction for AI as on 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/100&#43;High-Level-AI-Usecases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 15:50:00 +0530</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/100&#43;High-Level-AI-Usecases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6002-High-Level-UsesCases-AI.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HighLevel-UsesCases-AI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;150-high-level-ai-usecases---2020&#34;&gt;150 High Level AI Usecases - 2020&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, we frequently hear and read about AI and its role in shaping both our present and future. However, many people, even those who are tech-savvy, struggle to understand and answer some fundamental questions, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is AI (Artificial Intelligence)? Is it just another buzzword in technology?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What exactly can I do with AI?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How will AI affect my job and life?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In today’s volatile job market and business environment, what should I learn to secure my future?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I’m not a technology expert—will AI render me redundant?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where is AI? I only see electronic gadgets around me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is the relationship between AI, ML (Machine Learning), Automation, Robotics, IoT, and similar technologies?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And many other questions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are professionals with degrees in Data Science, AI, and ML who want to pursue their passion for building and researching meaningful, practical projects within limited timeframes and resources. Yet, many of them struggle to identify viable opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
