<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Economy on Agones</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/digital-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Economy on Agones</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:25:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/digital-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Business of Marketplaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/understanding-the-business-of-marketplaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hari@dasarpai.com (Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/understanding-the-business-of-marketplaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/images/dspost/dsp6236-Understanding-the-Business-of-Marketplaces.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Understanding the Business of Marketplaces&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-the-business-of-marketplaces-a-digital-economy-guide&#34;&gt;Understanding the Business of Marketplaces: A Digital Economy Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I have been puzzled by the online marketplace. As a result, I wanted to understand how it works, the different types of marketplaces, and their business models. During my research, it became overwhelming, so in this article, I focus on categorizing and listing important marketplaces to help my readers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rise of the internet has transformed the way businesses and individuals interact, giving birth to a vast and diverse ecosystem of online marketplaces. These platforms serve as digital hubs where buyers and sellers connect, facilitating the exchange of goods, services, and digital products. From e-commerce giants (like Amazon) to niche platforms catering to freelancers, creative professionals, and even AI enthusiasts, marketplaces have become an integral part of the global economy. This article categorizes and explores different types of marketplaces, highlighting their unique value propositions and industries they serve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
